The Crime of the Century!
The Anderson Tapes is a crime, thriller, action film directed by Sidney Lumet.
Thief Duke Anderson—just released from ten years in jail—takes up with his old girlfriend
in her posh apartment block, and makes plans to rob the entire building.
What he doesn't know is that his every move is being recorded on audio and
video, although he is not the subject of any surveillance.
Duke Anderson, played by Sean Connery.
Ingrid, played by Dyan Cannon.
Haskins, played by Martin Balsam.
Police Captain 'Iron Balls' Delaney, played by Ralph Meeker.
Pat Angelo, played by Alan King.
The Kid, played by Christopher Walken.
The Anderson Tapes is a 1971 American crime film directed by Sidney Lumet and starring Sean Connery and
featuring Dyan Cannon, Martin Balsam, Ralph Meeker, Garrett Morris, Margaret Hamilton, and Alan King.
The screenplay by Frank Pierson was based on the 1970 epistolary novel of the same name by
Lawrence Sanders, which consists primarily of transcripts of tape recordings.
The film is scored by Quincy Jones and marks the
feature film debut of Christopher Walken.
It was the first major film to focus on the pervasiveness of electronic surveillance,
from security cameras in public places to hidden recording devices.
The film explores themes of new york city, robbery, based on
novel or book, internal affairs, surveillance.
The tone is intense.